<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
     <title> Ward Family History Plan </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html</link>
     <description> Where Generations Meet </description>
     <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 06:57:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
     <title> Help your family and others do family history work </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Help%20your%20family%20and%20others%20do%20family%20history%20work</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 02:11:41 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:100;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS8.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>As Church members, we do have a divinely appointed responsibility to seek out our ancestors and compile family histories. This is far more than an encouraged hobby, because the ordinances of salvation are necessary for all of God’s children. We are to identify our own ancestors who died without receiving the ordinances of salvation. We can perform the ordinances vicariously in temples, and our ancestors may choose to accept the ordinances. We are also encouraged to help ward and stake members with their family names. It is breathtakingly amazing that, through family history and temple work, we can help to redeem the dead. </p><cite>Sealing and Healing by Elder Dale G. Renlund, April 2018</cite></blockquote>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Add new names to your family tree on FamilySearch.org </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Add%20new%20names%20to%20your%20family%20tree%20on%20FamilySearch.org</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 06:51:50 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-none" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/quentin_l_cook.jpeg"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>In the worldwide membership of the Church, fifty-one percent of adults currently do not have both parents in the Family Tree section of the Church’s <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a> Internet site. Sixty-five percent of adults do not have all four grandparents listed. Remember, we without our roots and branches cannot be saved. Church members need to obtain and input this vital information.” </p><cite>Roots and Branches by Elder Quentin L. Cook, April 2014</cite></blockquote><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:80%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS12.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Do original research to find new family names </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Do%20original%20research%20to%20find%20new%20family%20names</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 06:48:34 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS11.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p>Family history research becomes more challenging in each generation further removed from your own.</p><h2 class="">Tips for Family History Research</h2><ul><li>Develop a system that works for you</li><li>Be well organized to make your efforts more effective</li><li>Take advantage of records from all sources</li><li>Have a system for tracking your progress</li></ul><p><p style="margin-bottom: 50px;"></p></p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>Family history requires effort and work on our part. It takes faith to engage in and continue with the work of family history research and submission of names for temple ordinances. </p><cite>Introduction to Family History Teacher Manual</cite></blockquote><div class="alert alert-primary " style="width:100%;"><h2 class="">Sources of family history information</h2><ul><li>Computer records</li><li>Civil records</li><li>Birth certificates </li><li>Marriage certificates </li><li>Death certificates </li><li>Census records</li><li>Immigration records</li><li>Naturalization records</li><li>Probate records</li><li>Land records</li><li>Military records</li><li>Church records </li></ul></div>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Upload photos, stories, and documents to FamilySearch.org </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Upload%20photos%2C%20stories%2C%20and%20documents%20to%20FamilySearch.org</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 06:44:45 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:50%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS10.1.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p>This feature allows us to preserve and share photos, documents, and stories about our ancestors</p><ul><li>Faces in photos can be identified and linked to the person’s profile in Family Tree.</li><li>Photos and stories can also be easily shared social media and email.</li></ul><p><p style="margin-bottom: 150px;"></p></p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>Photos and stories matter, because they “personally teach us time-honored principles from those who have gone on before us, like the value of hard work, dealing with life’s ups and downs and the impact of choices.” </p><cite><a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a> managing director Dennis Brimhall</cite></blockquote><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:80%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS10.2.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:80%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS10.3.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Clean up family tree names (adding sources, merging duplicate records, etc.) on FamilySearch.org </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Clean%20up%20family%20tree%20names%20(adding%20sources%2C%20merging%20duplicate%20records%2C%20etc.)%20on%20FamilySearch.org</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 02:11:40 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS9.1.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><ul><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a>.org has many features to help ensure accuracy</li><li>Keeping family tree information clean and accurate helps us get more temple work done</li><li>By not checking sources, people inadvertently do temple work for none existent individuals</li><li>By not checking for duplicates, we inadvertently do the temple work for the same individuals over and over again</li></ul><p><p style="margin-bottom: 80px;"></p></p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>The practice of keeping accurate records increases the efficiency and accuracy of family history work.” </p><cite>Introduction to Family History Student Manual chapter 4</cite></blockquote><h2 class="">Adding Sources</h2><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS9.2.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><ul><li>Making sure all the information in our family tree is backed up by sources is important to help ensure accuracy</li><li>I have also found that seeking out sources for the information already in <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a> has been an incredibly fruitful way to find the names of new individuals to add to the tree and do temple work for</li><li>See this article on adding sources: <a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.familysearch.org/blog/en/add-sources/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://www.familysearch.org/blog/en/add-sources/</a> </li></ul><h2 class="">Merging Records</h2><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:100;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS9.3.jpeg"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><ul><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a>.org allows users to merge the records when there are two for the same person</li><li>You can initiate this merge feature on your own and FS.org will also point out “possible duplicates” that it finds</li><li>During the merge, <ul><li>Users choose which data to keep and which to archive</li><li>Users are shown all of the information and relationships from both records</li><li>Users compare each piece of information and choose which to keep and which to archive</li><li>Users should consult source records (birth certificates, marriage records, etc.) when making these decisions</li></ul></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a> records all merge actions in a change history so that they can be undone if necessary</li></ul>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Do temple ordinances for deceased family members names that you researched and found </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Do%20temple%20ordinances%20for%20deceased%20family%20members%20%20names%20that%20you%20researched%20and%20found</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 02:12:15 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-none" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/Gary_E._Stevenson.jpg"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>As you engage in this work, I think you will find that the Lord is in its details. An experience demonstrates this. I recently learned of a mother who regularly escorted her children to the temple to perform proxy baptisms. On this particular day, as this family completed their baptisms and were leaving the temple, a man entered the baptistry area with a large batch of his own family names. Realizing there was no one remaining in the baptistry to assist with these family names, a temple worker caught the departing family and asked the children if they would consider reentering and changing once again to assist with these baptisms. They willingly agreed and went back in. As the children were baptized, their mother, listening, began to recognize the names and soon, to the amazement of all, realized the man’s batch of family names were deceased ancestors of her family as well. A sweet, tender mercy for them. </p><cite>Where Are the Keys and Authority of the Priesthood? by Elder Gary E. Stevenson, April 2016</cite></blockquote>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Find family names and print temple cards from FamilySearch.org </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Find%20family%20names%20and%20print%20temple%20cards%20from%20FamilySearch.org</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 02:12:14 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:100;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS6.1.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS6.2.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p><p style="margin-bottom: 100px;"></p></p><ol><li>Click on green temple icon and press the “Request” button to reserve the name for temple work.</li><li>Once reserved, go to the “Temple” tab in the main menu</li><li>Click the name you want to print, then the “Print” button</li><li>Print the card on you home printer and bring it to the temple to do the ordinance work for your ancestor</li></ol><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:100;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS6.3.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>Many faithful Saints have done the work of researching their family lines and are using the reserve feature of <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a> to hold the ordinances for their own family members to serve as proxy. The intent of reserving names is to allow a reasonable period of time for individuals to perform ordinances for ancestors …. Ancestors who have been found are no doubt anxious and thrilled when their names are cleared for ordinances. </p><cite>The Joy of Redeeming the Dead by Elder Richard G. Scott, Oct 2012</cite></blockquote><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:50%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS6.4.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Index names (digitize records) </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Index%20names%20(digitize%20records)</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 02:12:14 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS5.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><ul><li>The indexing process transforms information from old genealogical records into digital format</li><li>People doing indexing look at images of genealogical documents and type what they see into forms on their computers.</li><li>Indexing makes records available and searchable. </li><li>Thanks to indexing, searches that used to take hours, days, or even years can now be accomplished in seconds.</li></ul><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS5.1.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><h2 class="">To do indexing:</h2><ol><li>Go to <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a>.org</li><li>Then click on “Indexing” in the main menu to get started</li></ol>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Attend the temple to perform saving ordinances such as baptisms, endowment, and sealings </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Attend%20the%20temple%20to%20perform%20saving%20ordinances%20such%20as%20baptisms%2C%20endowment%2C%20and%20sealings</link>
     <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 19:12:59 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-none" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/quentin_l_cook.jpeg"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>“The primary blessings of the temple are the ordinances of exaltation. The gospel plan is about exaltation and encompasses making and keeping sacred covenants with God. Except for baptism and confirmation, these ordinances and covenants are performed and received in the temple for the living. For the dead, all the saving ordinances and covenants are received in the temple.” </p><cite>See Yourself in the Temple by Elder Quentin L. Cook, April 2016</cite></blockquote><h2 class="">The Temple is Centered in the Savior</h2><p>Everything in the <a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/temples?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">temple</a> points us to Jesus Christ. </p><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-none" style="width:align=center;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/draw-nearer-to-christ.jpg"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>The temple lies at the center of strengthening our faith and spiritual fortitude because the Savior and His doctrine are the very heart of the temple. Everything taught in the temple, through instruction and through the Spirit, increases our understanding of Jesus Christ. His essential ordinances bind us to Him through sacred priesthood covenants. Then, as we keep our covenants, He endows us with His healing, strengthening power. </p><cite>President Russell M. Nelson, “The Temple and Your Spiritual Foundation,” General Conference, October 2021</cite></blockquote>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Have a temple recommend </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Have%20a%20temple%20recommend</link>
     <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 19:26:43 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-none" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS3.jpg"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p>Please meet with Bishop Jackson to renew or obtain your temple recommend.</p><h2 class="">Articles</h2><ul><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/liahona/2022/01/afc-eng-local-pages/local-news-002?id=title1&amp;lang=eng#title1" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Armed with My Temple Recommend</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/liahona/2019/01/asa-eng-local-pages/local-news-001?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Always Having a Temple Recommend</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/liahona/2021/01/nzl-eng-local-pages/local-news-004?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Elder Yamashita Invites Church Members to Always Hold a Temple Recommend</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://newsroom.churchofjesuschrist.org/article/october-2019-general-conference-temple-recommend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Church Updates Temple Recommend Interview Questions</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://news-ug.churchofjesuschrist.org/article/hold-a-temple-recommend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hold a Temple Recommend</a></li></ul><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>We pray that each of you, regardless of your current circumstances, will counsel with your bishop and be worthy of a temple recommend. We are grateful that many more members are preparing to go to the temple. There has been a significant increase in the number of worthy adult temple recommend holders for many years. Limited-use recommends for worthy youth have increased dramatically over the last two years. Clearly the faithful core membership of the Church has never been stronger. </p><cite>Prepare to Meet God by Elder Quentin L. Cook, April 2018</cite></blockquote>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Visit FamilySearch.org and be familiar with website </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Visit%20FamilySearch.org%20and%20be%20familiar%20with%20website</link>
     <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 05:24:59 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:80%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FamilySearchLogo.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-right" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS2.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><ul><li>Is owned and operated by the Church</li><li>It’s the largest collection of genealogical and historical records in the world</li><li>Over 4 billion names</li><li>Has features to help you document important information about your ancestors</li><li>Is designed to help you find ordinances that are ready to perform for your ancestors</li><li>Can show you where your ancestors are from on a world map</li><li>Has free phone/email support</li></ul><h1 class="">Articles</h1><ul><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/2023/04/28de-hoyos?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Work of the Temple and Family History—One and the Same Work</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/2010/04/generations-linked-in-love?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Generations Linked in Love</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/1991/04/linking-the-family-of-man?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Linking the Family of Man</a></li><li><a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/video/personal-stories-temple-and-family-history/2021-02-0010-every-story-matters-to-familysearch-1080p?lang=eng" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Every Story Matters to FamilySearch</a></li></ul><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>The Lord has made available in our day remarkable resources that enable you to learn about and love [family history] work. <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a> is a collection of records, resources, and services easily accessible with personal computers and a variety of handheld devices, designed to help people discover and document their family history. </p><cite>The Hearts of the Children Shall Turn by David A. Bednar, Oct 2011</cite></blockquote><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-none" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/David_A_Bednar.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><h2 class="">Referring to <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a>.org</h2><blockquote class="tc-quote tc-big-quote"><p>The primary family history centers now are in our homes. Supplemental support for our family history research work also is available in our meetinghouses. </p><cite>Prepared to Obtain Every Needful Thing by Elder David A. Bednar, April 2019</cite></blockquote>]]>
     </description>
</item>
<item>
     <title> Have a Church Account and know how to log in to Church websites and mobile apps </title>
     <link>https://nnrt.site/WardFamilyHistoryPlan/index.html#Have%20a%20Church%20Account%20and%20know%20how%20to%20log%20in%20to%20Church%20websites%20and%20mobile%20apps</link>
     <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 06:53:32 GMT</pubDate>
     <description><![CDATA[<p>A vital first step in using the Church’s websites and mobile apps like <a class="tc-tiddlylink tc-tiddlylink-resolves" href="#FamilySearch">FamilySearch</a>.org and Family Tree is get a “Church Account”</p><p><figure class="image-basic image-align-center" style="width:30%;"> <img class=" tc-image-loading" src="./images/FS1.1.png"> <figcaption></figcaption> </figure> </p><div class="alert alert-primary " style="width:100%;"><ol><li>Go to <a class="tc-tiddlylink-external" href="https://account.churchofjesuschrist.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://account.churchofjesuschrist.org</a></li><li>Click Register for an LDS Account.</li><li>Fill in your membership record number and other personal details. </li><li>Complete your profile details.</li><li>Enter your display name </li><li>Enter your e-mail address.</li><li>Select your country and preferred language</li><li>Enter your desired user name and password.</li><li>Review and accept the Conditions of Use.</li><li>Review your account information.</li><li>Click Create Account.</li><li>Check your email </li><li>Open the email sent to you from the Church</li><li>Click on the link in your email.</li><li>Click Continue in the new window that pops up.</li></ol></div><p>Your Registration is complete! </p>]]>
     </description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
